so here we are it's nighttime but it's
dark mode it's a good time to talk about
dark things and we're going to
install the groove
box terminal settings for Mac
so this is my favorite theme if if if
you want to pick a different theme
that's cool but this is going to go
through the steps about how to set up a
theme there's lots of stuff on YouTube
about how to do this but I'm just I go
through it myself so let's do
it um let's go down
to uh the first thing we're going to do
is search for Groove
boox Mac
terminal and you'll be able to
see um you'll be able to see groupbox
Mac terminal theme this is actually an
extension
on I don't know how to say that name how
do you say that name it's kind of small
here let me zoom in
um but yeah it's this is the theme that
you're going to get um but this this
other extended one is seems pretty
good uh I used to have this in my DOT
files but I went ahead and look for a
new one so we're going to go here we're
going to click on this is if you want to
see it the dark one there's a light one
I why would you use that I have no idea
so we're going to use the light
one and we're going to click on dark
mode terminal here and we get this this
raw
data and we need to go into the raw data
for it actually let's I must have
clicked on something wrong let's see
here we go click on
this what is this download raw
file I don't know where all that stuff
came
from that's kind of
weird but find the way to download the
raw file all right so here we are we
have the file it's been downloaded if it
tries to name it. txt just name it
terminal
instead um and then then when you go
into the terminal app so you can you
know do what is it command space
terminal that'll open a terminal you get
this junky terminal
here and we can go ahead and close this
one then go to terminal
settings and I already have one imported
but I'm going to show you how to get it
in so you hit right here you do
import and then you go get the terminal
one that when you download I went to
downloads I had to authorize it and then
I'm going to hit on Terminal I'm going
to click on
open and here it all is now once you're
in here you're probably going to want to
improve the font type you might want to
click on default to set the default
defaults nice to have um because then
when you open up a new teral it doesn't
affect the current terminal by the way
you have to open a new terminal so if
you do
uh terminal new
window you can actually tell which one
or actually if you want to get good with
doing this you can just use uh command T
always opens a new terminal so now we
have a new terminal with group boox
colors uh you can't really see the
colors because we haven't done any
further customization on the terminal
there'll be other videos about how to do
that but now you can see the groove boox
terminal is is there uh I'm going to try
to see if there's anything here that I
can show you NOP I haven't put anything
on here this is a totally brush system
now but the thing is it's pretty tiny
the terminal is pretty tiny so let's go
ahead and make the terminal
larger um and you can do that going back
into the
services and I'm going to actually
change the
fonts uh in fact I'm going to go ahead
and download the
vantu mono font which is my
favorite um Google fonts iant
mono and I'm pretty sure you can
download
this get
font download
all and we're going to put it on where'
it Go did it get
downloaded all right so we're going to
double click it there's all the
fonts um and we can actually install all
of
them I think you can
just install them all I think you don't
have to in Click them all
if you click them then it'll say do you
want to install
it
install can you install all them at one
time I don't know let's
try let me try them
all open with new folder to selection
item open with bup hook move to
trash open with bup
hook let's see I think you have to put
them all in there there might be a way
to drag them all in can't sleep yeah and
then we're going to hit install we're
making video now so
install I don't know if it got them all
though I feel like it didn't I'm going
to do them all each
individually fun to font nope replaces
in
there so that one's
there uh this one double
click one two replace that one's already
there I guess that must have all been
there already I know I'm doing it the
slow way I don't it's fine just
whatever just need to get the fonts in
there okay so now that those fonts are
in
there um I'm going to go
change my
fonts
for uh for the
terminal back to the terminal here click
on font
change uh helvetica we're going to
change it to
auntu so
small to monu
regular character spacing I'm not going
to mess with any of that I am going to
increase the size though I usually do
about
22.
21 uh I mean it just changes on the day
I tend to change but that makes it it
usually makes it nicer for me to be able
to to stream it let's try 24 since
that's one of the standard ones these
are really small I apologize for that
not being able to see but that's why
we're doing this
um Regular 24 P okay so boom BTU man 24
let's try it let's make a new terminal
command
T and it didn't make my new one I maybe
maybe it's because I didn't save
it there it did it that's 24 I feel like
maybe we need it to be bigger what do
you
think what do you think do we need it to
be bigger than
that can you guys still see it let me
check
make sure you guys can still see can you
still see looks like you
can it's just it seems like it's like
really small let's go ahead and change
it let's make it a little bit
bigger
um let's make it bigger let's do 24
let's do
36 I maybe it's just because it's a
lower
resolution all right so let's do command
T wow that one's really big
that seems like it works
better now if I had t-o on here we could
actually measure it so we're going to go
ahead and not do that right now so let's
that's going to do it for us we got we
got the terminal set up we got it set up
to do Groove Box by default and um it's
ready the terminal is ready to start
customizing um I just want to end with a
note about why I'm using terminal versus
a laery versus Kitty versus um iterm
2 um the main reason is because the
terminal is built into the system it's
the most efficient uh it's the most
standardized and it's already on your
Mac um it turns out it's a lot faster
too somebody raised that issue to me the
other day when I was talking about iterm
2 and they're right they're right I went
back and tested it and I was like my
gosh the raw terminal is so much faster
than iterm 2 even though it 2 has got
some interesting fun things Integrations
with t-mo cut and paste and all that
it's not worth it it's not worth trading
this the raw speed of a terminal
especially when you start to use a
terminal the way I do uh and you will
you'll be starting to use a terminal a
lot a lot better more effectively so
that that's it this is the this has been
how to get your Mac terminal set
up um we'll do a separate video at some
point about how to get Windows terminal
set up how to get GI bash and that kind
of thing but for right now we this is I
wanted to get this video done about how
to do it so uh try to get group box you
can there's other ter there's other
themes out there you can try so solariz
is still a really popular one um there I
mean there's there's a bunch of them
people have definitely have preferences
for group box is my favorite it's the
easiest on the eyes so hopefully that'll
help you out see you later well next
time the next video is probably going to
be how to put Brew on your Mac and then
how to put t-u on your Mac Etc
so stay tuned for those